<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.olafkfreund.QuickWebApps</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>

  <name>Quick Web Apps</name>
  <summary>Turn any website into a desktop app</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Quick Web Apps is a native GTK4 and libadwaita manager for the GNOME
      desktop that turns websites into first-class applications. Paste a URL
      and it detects the site's Web App Manifest, fills in the name and icon
      for you, and installs a launcher into your app grid.
    </p>
    <p>Each web app runs in its own isolated window with its own profile and dock identity. Features include:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>PWA manifest auto-detection with automatic name, icon and theme</li>
      <li>Automatic icon download with a clean lettered fallback</li>
      <li>URL-scope confinement so off-scope links open in your browser</li>
      <li>Per-app user agent, ad-blocking, zoom and custom CSS</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.olafkfreund.QuickWebApps.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://olafkfreund.github.io/gnome-quick-web-apps/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/olafkfreund/gnome-quick-web-apps/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/olafkfreund/gnome-quick-web-apps</url>

  <developer id="io.github.olafkfreund">
    <name>olafkfreund</name>
  </developer>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>Network</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>web</keyword>
    <keyword>pwa</keyword>
    <keyword>launcher</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.1.14" date="2026-06-03">
      <description>
        <p>Removes the DRM-only streaming services (Netflix, Spotify, Apple Music, Disney+, Prime Video, Max, Tidal, Deezer) from the one-click templates: they require a Google-certified Widevine that no embeddable engine can provide, so they cannot play here. Everything that does not depend on DRM keeps working — YouTube, Twitch, SoundCloud and every non-streaming web app. The README explains the limitation and the investigation behind it.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.13" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes a crash on startup introduced in 0.1.12, where every web app could segfault when launched. The experimental DRM content-setting call is not supported by the embedded engine and has been disabled; DRM playback (Netflix, Apple Music) remains a known limitation being worked on, while the rest of the app works normally again.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.12" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>DRM playback fix: enables the "Sites can play protected content" setting via Chromium's protected-media content setting (the correct mechanism; earlier preference-based attempts had no effect). With a reused Widevine module present, Netflix, Apple Music and other DRM sites should now play instead of showing error M7701-1003.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.11" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>DRM playback fix follow-up: now that a reused Widevine module is detected, the app also enables Chromium's "Sites can play protected content" preference, which was leaving DRM blocked (Netflix error M7701-1003) even with the module present.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.10" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>DRM streaming (Apple Music, Netflix, Spotify Web) can now work: if you have a Chromium-family browser installed (Chrome, Chromium, Edge, Brave, Vivaldi), Quick Web Apps reuses its Widevine module automatically, since the embedded engine ships none. Without such a browser, DRM playback remains unavailable.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.9" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes a data-loss bug: deleting a web app no longer removes a custom icon you picked from elsewhere on disk. Imported icons are now copied into the app's own icon folder, and deleting an app only ever removes files it owns.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.8" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Web content is now crisp under fractional and HiDPI scaling (the render path is scale-aware, fixing blurry pages on compositors like Niri). Right-click inside a web app now shows a context menu (back/forward/reload and cut/copy/paste/select all), and the manager gains an About window so you can see which version you're running.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.7" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Deeper desktop integration: media apps now expose MPRIS controls (lock screen, media keys, Quick Settings); mail/chat apps can show an unread count badge on the dock; and background apps get a tray icon (show/quit) plus an optional "Start on login".</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.6" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Apps that share a login profile can now run at the same time, in one process with one shared session. New "Identify as" option spoofs the browser OS (Windows/macOS/Mobile/Custom) for services that require it. Clearer messaging when a profile is already in use.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.5" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Camera and microphone now work for video calls (Teams, Zoom, Meet) and are allowed by default. Adds a portable AppImage build for any distribution. Fixes blank toggle labels and makes the link-handling options readable.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.4" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>A big round of per-app controls and fixes: built-in ad/tracker blocker, force light/dark appearance, custom CSS, background-app mode (keep running for notifications), downloads to your Downloads folder, and a colored login-profile indicator in the manager and window. Permission policy for camera/mic and location, crisper rendering under fractional/HiDPI scaling, more reliable launcher paths, and groundwork for safe config migrations.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.3" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Media apps now have audio in the Flatpak sandbox. New tri-state link handling (keep everything in-window, or send other sites to the browser by registrable domain or exact host), with an allowlist that keeps sign-in/SSO and CAPTCHA pages in-window. Windows remember their size and zoom between sessions. Cleaner handling of declaratively-managed default-app settings.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.2" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Updated to the GNOME 50 runtime (47 and 48 are end-of-life). Apps with multi-domain sign-in (Microsoft Outlook/Teams, Slack) now keep authentication in-window by default, fixing broken logins. Link handling is more reliable.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.1" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Embedded service panels (Gmail's Tasks, Keep and Calendar) now load in-window instead of hanging or spawning stray windows. Mail and chat apps open links from messages in the system browser by default, while multi-domain sign-in still completes inside the app.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-06-01">
      <description>
        <p>Initial development release: create web apps with manifest autofill, automatic icons, and app-grid launcher install.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
